webcruiter.com 2019-06-08

# Privacy policy and terms of use for Webcruiter’s digital channels | Webcruiter

Last updated: 2018/06/21

At Webcruiter AS (“Webcruiter”), we are committed to protecting your personal information. This privacy policy and these terms of use (hereinafter referred to as “the Terms”) apply to our website www.webcruiter.com and our other digital services, such as blogs, e-mail subscriptions and the registration of information using forms (“digital channels”). This privacy policy and these terms of use do not apply to information registered in connection with the use of the Webcruiter recruitment solution, the Jucan job portal and Competence by Webcruiter.

The Terms govern everything we do in connection with the collection, processing and use of data for sales and marketing purposes. They also concern your rights to access, rectify and delete personal information about you. By using our digital channels you indicate your consent to the Terms. If you do not agree with the data practice described in the Terms, you should avoid using our digital channels.

## The website’s owner and contact details

**Name:** Webcruiter AS  
 **BRN:** 985 360 421  
 **E-mail:** [marked@webcruiter.no](mailto:marked@webcruiter.no "Send us an email")   
**Telephone:** [+47 22 30 11 50](tel:+4722301150 "Call us")  
 **Address:** Nydalsveien 12b, NO-0484 OSLO, Norway

Webcruiter AS protects your privacy in accordance with applicable laws and regulations, and is the data controller for your personal data. If you have any questions regarding our processing of personal data, please contact us by telephone on [+47 22 30 11 50](tel:+4722301150 "Call us") or by e-mail at [marked@webcruiter.no.](mailto:marked@webcruiter.no "Send us an email")

## Privacy policy

### 1\. Terms and expressions

First, let us define some important concepts:

  * Personal data is any information that can be directly or indirectly linked to you as an individual. Please see the section “What personal data do we process?” for information about the personal data we process.
  * Anonymised data is data from which all identifiable elements have been removed, so that it is no longer possible to link that data to you as an individual.
  * Processing of personal data is any use of personal data, including collection, storage, editing, compiling, distributing and deleting.
  * Our “digital channels” include our website and other digital services, including blogs, e-mail subscriptions and the registration of information using forms.

### 2\. How do we collect personal data?

The information we collect about you depends on which of our digital channels you use and what information you give us in connection with purchasing or registration or in other contexts.

We collect personal data that:

  * you disclose to us when you purchase or register for our services, subscribe to our newsletters and blogs, complete a form, or contact us.
  * is registered automatically when you use our digital channels.

You are not obligated to provide any personal data to us, but if you choose not to, we may not be able to provide our services to you, for instance because we cannot invoice you for the services or send you the information you request.

### 3\. What personal data do we process?

We may process personal data within the following categories:

  * Basic information, such as name, employer, job title and contact information.
  * Information about the customer relationship, such as order details and payment information, marketing permissions, and contact with customer support.
  * Information generated in connection with the use of digital channels, such as technical information about the device that you use when you visit our digital channels (including the date and time; the type of PC/mobile device, operating system and browser you use; IP addresses; screen resolution, etc.). The section “Navigation information” below provides more detailed information.
  * Information relating to the identification and registration of a customer or user, such as information about a user’s identity.
  * Any other information that is stored on the basis of your consent. In such cases, when we request your consent we will give you specific information about what data we store and what it is used for.

Our digital channels are not intended for or aimed at children under the age of 13. We do not intentionally store information about children under the age of 13. If you believe we have stored data about a child under the age of 13, you may contact us in writing so that we can delete the data.

### 4\. Navigation information

#### Cookies

We use cookies and similar technologies in our digital channels. Cookies help us to establish which parts of our digital channels are the most popular – for instance, which pages users visit, and the duration of each visit. This information is used for purposes such as the development and analysis of services and to target adverts on the Internet. You can read more about our use of cookies in section 9.

#### Log files

We automatically collect information about your device’s specifications and software and your visit to our website. This information may include your IP address, type of web browser, domain name, Internet service provider, files viewed (HTML pages, graphics, etc.), operating system, access time and where you were referred to our digital channels from.

#### Tracking pixels

We use tracking pixels (also known as clear GIFs, web beacons or web bugs) to help us improve our digital channels by telling us which content has been shown. Tracking pixels are small graphical elements with a unique identifier, with a similar function to cookies, and are used to track user behaviour on the Internet. Unlike cookies, which are stored on the user’s hard disk, tracking pixels are invisibly embedded in our digital channels or e-mails. This allows us to measure the effectiveness of our marketing. We link the information we gather from e-mails to customers’ personal information.

#### Advertising material

We may use third-party providers when we place adverts on the Internet. These companies use cookies and tracking pixels to collect information about your activities on this and other websites in order to offer you targeted advertising based on your interests. If you no longer wish to receive such information for the purpose of providing you with targeted advertising, you can opt out on <http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/>. Please note that opting out does not mean that you will no longer see any advertising online – you will still be exposed to generic advertising.

### 5\. How do we use your personal data?

We use the information that we store about you for the following purposes:

  * **To provide services:** We process personal data in order to perform and supply services to you. For example, your personal data is processed in connection with  

    * supplying content when you request it, such as e-mails addressed to recipients who have subscribed to newsletters or blog updates,
    * customer identification,
    * invoicing and payment handling, and
    * error correction, customer service and complaints handling.
  * **For development and analysis:** We process personal data in order to improve and develop our services and digital channels.
  * **For sales and marketing:** We use both anonymised data and personal data for marketing purposes, such as  

    * creating target audiences for marketing
    * adapting and directing marketing, such as by providing recommendations or targeted content via our digital channels
    * sending newsletters and other forms of direct marketing when permitted based on your consent or applicable legislation
    * marketing analyses, customer satisfaction surveys, etc.
    * “cleansing” contact information with Facebook, Google, LinkedIn and other digital organisations so that we can communicate with you and other users through these channels
  * **For data security and to prevent misuse of services:** We may process personal data in order to ensure that our digital channels are secure. We may also process personal data to detect or prevent various types of misuse.
  * **To comply with legislation:** We process personal data to comply with our legal obligations, for example for accounting purposes and in order to provide information to competent authorities when we are required to do so by Norwegian law.
  * **For other purposes with your consent:** We may process your personal data for any other purpose for which you have specifically given us consent.

### 6\. How do we protect your data?

Protecting your personal data is a high-priority duty for us, and we work constantly to protect personal data and other confidential information. Our security work includes taking physical, technical and administrative measures, including the protection of personnel, information, IT infrastructure, internal and external networks, and office buildings and technical facilities.

It also involves carrying out regular risk assessments and reviewing various factors such as available technology, business needs and legal requirements. We do this to ensure that we always have sufficient security measures in place, for instance to prevent personal data from falling into the wrong hands.

### 7\. To whom do we supply your personal data?

We may provide personal data to:

  * Data processors who work for us as subcontractors and who process your data on our behalf. These subcontractors cannot use personal data for any purpose other than to perform the service agreed with us. We take special precautions to ensure that our subcontractors comply with these Terms and with Norwegian data protection legislation, and in particular where the data processor is located in a country outside Norway or the EU/EEA area.
  * Other parties with your consent.

We may also supply information:

  * In cases where we are required to do so by law, such as in response to court orders or as required by the police or other public authorities, in accordance with strict, predefined processes.
  * In connection with transfers of undertakings, for example as part of mergers, acquisitions, sales of our assets or the transfer of services to another company. In such cases you will be notified by e-mail and/or see a notification in our digital channels about any change in ownership, the use of your personal data and any choices you may have regarding your personal data.

### 8\. How long do we store your data?

We will store your personal data for as long as necessary in order to fulfil the purposes stated in the Terms, unless a longer retention period is required or permitted in accordance with applicable legislation.

Personal data is stored for as long as you have an active relationship with us or our digital channels, or until you ask us to forget you and to delete stored information about you. We define a relationship with us or our digital channels as (i) being our customer, (ii) having consented to receiving marketing information from us, (iii) having actively requested contact with us via social media, electronic message or electronic form, or (iv) being active in our digital channels after you have given your consent. The relationship is defined as active if it has been exercised during the previous 24 months.

The storage of anonymised data is not subject to such restrictions or requirements. Furthermore, we endeavour to ensure that personal data and other customer information is kept up to date and accurate, and that we do not store information that is not required for the purposes of the processing of the personal data.

### 9\. How do we use cookies?

We use cookies and similar technologies in our digital channels. Cookies help us to establish which parts of our digital channels are the most popular – for instance, which pages users visit, and the duration of each visit. This information is used for purposes such as the provision, development and analysis of services and to target adverts on the Internet.

Click here for information about how we use cookies.

We may combine information from cookies with other data we have registered about you and your customer relationship when permitted by applicable legislation or when you have given us your consent.

By using our digital channels through a browser whose settings make it possible to save cookies on your device, you give your consent for our use of cookies.  
Our websites may include links to third-party websites, products and services, including social media (for example, Facebook’s social plugins). Third-party services or third-party applications made available on our websites are subject to the relevant third parties’ privacy policies. We encourage you to familiarise yourself with these third parties’ privacy practices.

### 10\. What are your rights and options?

You have the right to:

  * know what information we have registered about you,
  * demand that inaccurate, unnecessary, incomplete or out-of-date personal data be rectified or deleted,
  * withdraw or limit any consent to process personal data that you have given us – however, please note that this may mean that we can no longer provide some of our services to you,
  * deactivate the collection of data via Google Analytics.

We are committed to running a responsible and sustainable enterprise. If you believe that we are not complying with these Terms or applicable legislation, you may complain to us, or optionally to the Norwegian Data Protection Authority.

### 11\. Changes to these Terms

From time to time, as our enterprise and tools develop, we may need to update these Terms. We encourage you to review these Terms regularly. In the event of major changes, we may also attempt to contact you directly through available channels, such as by e-mail or by notifications in our digital channels.

## Terms of use

By using our digital channels, you accept these terms of use.

### 1\. Permitted use

You may only use content from our digital channels for non-commercial, personal purposes, and/or to learn about Webcruiter’s products and services, and exclusively in accordance with these terms of use.

### 2\. Forbidden use

By using our digital channels, you undertake not to:

  * Use our digital channels in contravention with these terms of use.
  * Copy, modify or imitate this work, deconstruct or dismantle the page, or in any other way attempt to reveal the source code or permit a third party to do so.
  * Sell, assign, re-license, distribute, use commercially, or in any other way transfer rights to content or services or make such available to a third party.
  * Use or start an automated system, including, but not limited to “robots”, “spiders” or “offline readers” that use this site in a manner that sends more requests to the server during a given period than it would be reasonable to expect that a human would be able to generate by using a normal web browser.
  * Use our digital channels in a manner that damages, deactivates, overloads or impairs our channels or interrupts other parties’ use of and benefit from the channels.
  * Mirror or include the channels wholly or partly in any other channel.
  * Attempt to gain unauthorised access to our digital channels.
  * Gain access to our digital channels in any manner other than via the frameworks offered by Webcruiter for access to those channels.
  * Use our digital channels for any purpose or in any way that is prohibited by these terms.
  * Attempt any unauthorised use of the content or of the channels that could contravene patent, copyright, trademark or other laws.

### 3\. Copyright and trademarks

Our digital channels are protected by applicable intellectual property law and other legislation, including on the protection of trademarks and copyright. Our digital channels, including all intellectual works in the channels, belong to and are the property of Webcruiter or its licensor (where relevant). Webcruiter retains all copyright to such content. The content must not be copied, reproduced, amended, published, uploaded, posted, transferred, executed or distributed in any way without specific permission. You undertake not to amend, hire, lend, sell, distribute, broadcast or create derivative works of the content on this website, whether in part or in its entirety, in any manner. Webcruiter’s logo and other marks used by Webcruiter from time to time are trademarks and are Webcruiter’s property.

### 4\. Information and materials you register and share with us

You guarantee that you have the necessary rights to the materials you register or share in our digital channels and that you authorise us to use and publish this material. You guarantee that you have no intention of deceiving or providing misleading information, and that the material you provide does not contravene these terms of use.

### 5\. Links to third-party websites

Links to or information about third-party websites are only intended to be for your convenience. If you use these links you will leave our digital channels. The presence of such links or information does not indicate that Webcruiter supports, recommends or sponsors such third-party websites or the information they contain. Webcruiter is not responsible for the availability of such websites. Webcruiter is not responsible or liable for such websites or the content they contain. If you use the links to external websites, you will leave our digital channels and be subject to the terms of use and privacy practices applicable to those websites.

### 6\. Downloading files

Webcruiter cannot guarantee that files made available for download via our digital channels are free from viruses or other malicious code, files or programs.

### 7\. Disclaimer/limitation of liability

Webcruiter and our service providers, licensors and suppliers give no guarantee of the suitability, reliability, availability, validity, security or accuracy of our digital channels or their content. All information, software, products, services and graphical elements are offered “as is”, without any form of guarantee.

To the extent possible under current legislation, Webcruiter and its service providers, licensors and suppliers can under no circumstances be held responsible for any loss or damage in any form that may arise as a result of or in connection with the use of our digital channels, irrespective of whether this is based on a contract, compensation, omission or liability, even if Webcruiter or any of Webcruiter’s partners have been informed of the possibility of damage.

### 8\. Compensation

You acknowledge and agree that you will be personally responsible for your own behaviour in our digital channels. You agree to compensate, defend and indemnify Webcruiter and its parent company, subsidiaries, associates, partners, licensors, employees, agents and all third-party information services from and against all claims, losses, expenses, damages and costs (including, but not limited to, direct, incidental, consequential and indirect damages) and realistic legal expenses as a result of or due to use, misuse or lack of ability to use our digital channels or content or any breach of these terms.
